# **ANDREW PENNINGTON, MBA**

Accounting professional with extensive experience in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, forecasting and budget development. A proven leader recognized for sound decision-making abilities, strong analytical skills, financial acuity, and outstanding performance developed from a solid professional background in Accounting and Computer Software. Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint as well as systems experience with PeopleSoft Financials, NetSuite, QuickBooks Online and Desktop, Sage Intacct, SAP Financial Accounting, Peachtree, Workday ERP, Banner ERP and multiple proprietary AS400 and mainframe-based accounting and inventory systems.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### National Park College - Hot Springs, Arkansas

03/2021 - 03/2024

Controller

Oversee financial operations and higher education reporting for a large community college. Direct staff of accountants compiling financial reports based on financial statements and implementing policies and procedures for financial reporting and operation.

- Assist management with important financial decisions.
- Prepare financial documents such as business reports, forecasts, and statements to understand the business's economic state.
- Supervise employees who work under the controller in preparing financial reports and budgets.
- Analyze revenues and expenses to ensure they are recorded appropriately monthly.
- Management and development of policy and procedures including documentation and monitoring of the internal controls, sales and use tax reporting controls, and fixed asset process, policy, and procedures.

# Garland County Sheriff's Office - Hot Springs, Arkansas

06/2019 - 03/2021

#### Finance Manager

Directed and delegated accounting responsibilities among multiple accountants. Developed budgeting system based on forecasting algorithms and trending data. Coordinated transparent accounting processes to meet federal, state, county, and city policies.

- Prepared financial reports, developed budgets, and performed variance analysis in accordance with business plan objectives.
- Responsible for developing, reviewing, and operating within budget, forecast and P&L guidelines.
- Performed operational and financial audits to assess and evaluate the adequacy of internal controls.
- Account and project management responsibilities including contract negotiations and leveraging relationships with all external entities.

#### Hot Springs Tax Services - Hot Springs, Arkansas

05/2015 - 06/2019

### Owner / Accountant

Provided fully integrated accounting and financial analysis services to multiple corporations and small businesses. These services include the preparation of the general ledger month-end close, and presentation of the financial statement results to the owners and directors of clients in the construction, retailing, and almost all blue-collar industries as well as non-profit entities.

- Prepared financial statements, monthly account reconciliations and supporting schedules according to monthly close schedule, facilitate and complete all monthly close procedures.
- Analyzed revenues and expenses to ensure they are recorded appropriately monthly.
- Worked with federal, state, and local tax agencies to guarantee low audit risk among clients and strengthen tax planning policies.

## Magic Springs Water and Theme-Park - Hot Springs, Arkansas

06/2009 - 05/2015

Finance & Accounting Manager

Responsible for the accounting and financial reporting for business 12M revenue annually. Complete accountability for reporting process with annual reviews by management and corporate teams.

- Prepared financial reports, developed budgets, and performed variance analysis in accordance with business plan objectives.
- Responsible for month-end close process, along with monthly account reconciliation
- Built accurate procedures and accounting standards based around GAAP and operational needs.
- Coordinated and implemented daily revenue report for use in daily operational decision. Insured report was accurate to the highest degree each day.
- Created and managed budget for 20+ departments, with 10 department heads including revenue, operations, maintenance, rides, water park, concert venue, and others.
- Responsible for interviewing, hiring, and training 20+ employees including 16 seasonal employees.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

Master of Business Administration (MBA) - Accounting, University of Arkansas at Little Rock – 3.5 GPA Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA) - Accounting, University of Arkansas at Little Rock – 3.7 GPA

#### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS AND TRAINING

Office Specialist: Excel, Microsoft Certified Payroll Specialist (CPS), NACPB Certified Payroll Professional (CPP), APA Workday Finance and HR Certified, Workday